Hey everyone, thanks for listening to
the Grow Your Life podcast. My name is
Jeremiah Kowski. On this podcast, I help
coaches, mentors, and trainers scale
their businesses and make more money
online to reach their goals. On this
episode, I want to talk about how do you
keep your cool on camera and stop
worrying what everybody else thinks when
you're recording. This is a skill that
I've learned over time and it's
something that I've developed and I want
to pass on to you some of the lessons
that I've learned in this episode.
Number one, the biggest thing is is that
the more you do it, the better that it's
going to get. The more often that you
show up on camera, the more you share,
the better it's going to get. I used to
be so terrified all the time when I
would sit down to record stuff on camera
that I would mess up, that I would say
the wrong things, that I would make
mistakes, that I wasn't perfectly
positioned on screen here and things
like that that I maybe would look on
camera. Like I have some notes right
here that I'm reading that are helping
keeping me on track. And that's one of
the things that I talk about for people
is that if you're using notes or things
like that, you can actually share live
with people that you're using notes. You
can kind of remove the pressure of
needing to be perfect all the time by
being able to do that. And so that's one
of the biggest things that helps you get
out of your head and out of your own way
when you do that. We can't let the fear
of judgment of other people stop us from
showing up. And the more consistent that
you show up, the better things are going
to be. I think one of the biggest
problems that we have in our in our uh
culture, in our society, and as a coach
and mentor, is that we put way too much
pressure on ourselves to be perfect when
we show up on camera with people. We put
this belief and pressure that you got to
be perfect every time that you show up.
And that if you're not perfect, well,
gosh, you shouldn't even show up at all.
And this is just not even rooted in
reality because there's no such thing as
perfection. There's nobody that is
perfect enough out there when they're
creating content, when they're creating
value that they're putting out there
that
can be perfect all the time. You're
going to make mistakes. You're going to
mess up. You're going to pause. You're
going to have stuff like that. You're
going to have you might say the wrong
things. You might have the wrong cadence
or tone. I have found that if I put the
pressure on myself that I have to be
perfect, I don't even show up very well.
I don't even show up in a way that's
going to serve people. And so I want you
to realize I know maybe you have been
raised a different way. Maybe you've
been taught a different way. Maybe
you've experienced differently in your
life or your business that you have to
be a certain way. Understand that you
don't have to be a certain way that you
can
change this behavior about yourself.
It's not a spirit of excellence.
Perfectionism isn't excellence at all.
Per perfectionism is quite something
entirely different. It's unreasonable.
It's unrealistic. And it's just a recipe
simply of failure because there's no
such thing as being perfect in your
life. And so understand
that you're not always going to be
perfect. Now, how can you show up as
close to perfect as possible? Well, it's
getting out of your head and getting out
of your own way of that having that
perfection. What I do is this is I have
a couple of different techniques I do.
Number one, the first thing is I
actually give myself the ability, the
opportunity, and the permission to not
be perfect. The permission to where I
can flub up. I can mess up. I don't need
to do everything perfectly. And it's
okay for me to just be me when I'm
showing up on camera or on screen with
people. Number two is that I don't uh
worry about that. But what I do is I
visualize that everybody that I'm
talking to is my ideal audience. They're
not judgmental. So when I'm recording a
podcast like this or I'm recording a
course or I'm doing anything like that,
I'm imagining
that the people that I'm talking to, I'm
talking to you right now are
they love everything that I'm talking
about. They lean on every word that I
share. They they absolutely just think
that I'm the best when I'm recording
stuff and and and I literally have a
positive experience that I anchor
everything that I'm doing when I'm
recording it. that I just imagine that
I'm talking with my favorite clients or
my friends that are going to truly love
what I'm talking about. They're not
going to judge me harshly. And by the
way, if people want to judge you
harshly, let them. There's actually a
great book. It's by Mel Robbins. It's
called The Let Them theory. And it's all
about just like letting people do or
think whatever they want. And you don't
need to control it. Our need to control
other people and their perceptions and
their thoughts about us and then tying
that into a spirit of excellence or
desire that we have to do everything
perfect is truly one of the biggest
things that stops us from even showing
up the way that we need to in our lives
and our businesses. What you want to do
is you want to create a sense of calm in
your body. And there's two senses of
this. Number one, you want calm and then
you want a flow state. So calm is
created when you get out of the brain's
natural fight or flight. And one of the
best things you can do for this is you
can even learn certain breathing
exercises or mindfulness techniques to
be able to do this where you breathe in,
you can focus on your breath in your
belly while you're breathing in and that
will help calm you down and calm your
nerves down. Another thing that I like
to do sometimes is that I will actually
record content. I'll take a I'll take a
nap or something like that and then get
on and record the content as soon as I
wake up. something like that. These are
all little techniques that I've learned
over time that have helped me be able to
get out of my head and out of my own
way. Now, let's say that you're
struggling to know exactly what to talk
about. Well, what I do is I'll use a
bullet point outline or just some notes
or points that I want to talk about.
I'll use chat GPT to help me put these
together. I'll talk with chat about what
I want to share. And I actually use a
prompt sometimes where it says, "Okay,
if if I was creating a one-hour TED
talk, make me an outline for everything
that I'm talking about." In fact, this
podcast right here actually did that
before this. I used all of the
techniques for this episode that I talk
about when doing this to share with you
to be transparent to show you that. And
that's the other thing, too, is that you
can be transparent with your audience
and say, "Hey, listen. I'm using some
notes here. I'm talking through some
notes uh just to keep me on track." And
so, if you see me looking down, that's
exactly what that is.
You don't need to be perfect. You don't
need everything to be perfect. Realize
that your goal is to transform people's
lives and to connect with people. It's
not to be graded on how good you showed
up or how perfect your voice sounded or
trying to impress people. Instead of
trying to impress people, say that you
want to impress upon them, that you have
something valuable to share. And that's
what your goal is, is that you're
looking to share something valuable with
people rather than do everything
perfect. If you can learn how to anchor
yourself in the positive feelings of
connecting with a friend, connecting
with somebody that you truly love,
connecting with somebody that really
loves you, and
you can breathe through it. You can
reframe the experience as a positive
away from I need to impress people.
rather I'm trying to share my value,
you'll show up so much better and more
consistently. And then if you remind
yourself constantly of this and then
here's the last thing that I do is I
create an environment in my life where
this happens for me. I create my own
destiny in this is that I start to
develop and I create patterns and
frameworks and I notice what gets me
into that quote unquote mood for
recording more consistently. What gets
me into that state of mind where I feel
confident that I can show up to the best
of my ability and I cultivate that and
I've actually created like scenarios. I
create the scenarios in my life and in
my mind to be able to show up to be able
to create that and to be more
consistent. And as I've done that, I've
been able to do more, accomplish more,
and be more in how I show up in my
videos. and they just come across a lot
easier. They come across a lot better
when I record. It connects with people
better. And I let the I let the pressure
off. I take the pressure off of needing
to be perfect. And I just share from my
heart rather than from my mind. I am
trying to stop sharing from like the
brain that's all logical and needs to be
perfect and rather I let it flow from my
heart and I share my voice so that I can
impact people. The last thing is I
believe and I know that my message is
going to change people's lives. It's
going to impact them. If I can pass this
on to one person, it will impact them on
a huge level. And so I always remind
myself of that is that the work that I
do is that it impacts people on a huge
level. That it makes them
that it'll make them and their families
and their bloodlines
better overall. And I don't let the fear
hold me back because I keep that in mind
as about the people that I'm impacting
overall. I also use resources like this
podcast episode. You could literally
save this episode,
listen to it, play it back
yourself in your dayto-day when you get
stuck and it will remind you of exactly
what you can do. It's a process that you
can literally go through in a framework
that can help you every day. every time
you record something to show up better.
Listen, I hope this has helped you. I
hope that this has encouraged you. If it
has, share it with somebody. Don't keep
it to yourself. Don't hold it in. And
listen, I'd love to see you as well
inside of my Wealthy Coach Academy
program and maybe inside of our one of
our VIP programs in the future. I'd love
to help you and come alongside you and
work with you to be able to grow your
business to know exactly what to say,
how to say it, and how to put everything
together to help you reach your goals.
We'll talk soon everybody. Have a good
one. Grow your life.
[Music]
[Applause]